# Samuel Muiruri

Python / Django developer (Full Stack) Email: muiruri.samuel@gmail.com

**Age:** 27 **Phone No:** +254 738 940 064

**LinkedIn:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-muiruri-a5235532/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-muiruri-a5235532/</a> **Stackoverflow:** <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Six-wars">https://github.com/Six-wars</a>

I've got +5 years experience in Django and almost expertise level in Python.

I have experience working alone on projects and in a team of developers.

Comfortable with front-end development and have been left in charge of running, migrating and maintaining server of popular site(s).

# **Tools worth mentioning**

- ➤ **Nginx:** familiar with it, use it always.
- **Gunicorn:** also familiar and use it mainly.
- > **AWS:** migrated a django site to AWS
- **Django 1.8:** *latest version I've used so far.*
- > **Jquery & Bootsrap:** *my preferred front-end tools.*
- **django-allauth:** used to setup Oauth accounts for facebook, twitter, and more.
- **django-rest-framework:** worth mentioning, used on a demo site only.
- ➤ **matplotlib:** *I* used it to create a few simple graphs, from the docs know it's full capabilities.
- ➤ **reportlab:** *I* used it to create Movie Ticket pdf's for KenyaBuzz
- ➤ **Angularjs:** have used it only to get a feel of how it works
- **virtualenv:** implemented it on pluscolor.co.ke where Django site runs on virtualenv
- **Selenium:** *useful for automation browser processes and testing user activity*

### **Education**

**K.C.S.E** (Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education) **Grade:** C+ : 2006 - 2009

*Kenyatta University:* **Diploma in Information Technology** : 2011 – 2012 (discontinued)

In the last year (2012) I was working full time at Lamu Software as a Django Developer, since my intent was to finish the course and pursue a course in Computer Science I re-evaluated and realized with skills from the field I could bridge into the course later on.

#### **Udacity:** <u>udacity.com</u>

Since it launched I've taken courses offered there like "Introduction to Artificial Intelligence".

*In my free time taking a course in Machine Learning.* 

# **Experience**

Before start of work history I worked for "Lamu Software" which was a startup specializing in developing sites using Django. I started here as a junior developer, but the company later on closed.

After leaving Lamu Software and in between then and now I have worked on a number of small projects notable one; using "Vidi Reports" which returns facial recognition data such as; age, sex, mood, watching/not watching ... in json & send the data to django so on a screen (with a camera) show user based ads. For example have one ad for men and another for women and based on the majority gender play the ad.

# Kenya Buzz – <u>kenyabuzz.com</u>

2015 - 2017

I've worked here as a django developer in charge of maintaining the day to day running of the site. During this time I've honed my skills as a front-end dev and also improved in backend dev too.

Kenya Buzz is a *lifestyle website* which has lifestyle articles, events happening in Kenya, movie listing and the option to buy movie tickets for some theatres in Kenya. At the time I joined the ticketing was handled by another provider then hosted on the site using iframe. I since then moved it in house, set up the ticketing; so you can select a seat, pay and get a ticket sent to your email.

I also worked on editing the front end to a more modern look.

**Note:** Early this year 2017, Nation Media Group acquired Kenya Buzz in a merger, from this came the task to migrate the site to AWS and later switch to PHP. Since I left they have finished testing and launching the new site.

Alix Grubel - CEO alix@kenyabuzz.com +254 733 620 998

# Kazi Lynk – kazilynk.com

2017 - to date

Kazi Lynk is a job listing site that matches jobs to job seekers and also lists services that target the Kenyan Market.

Soft Launch on October 2017.

**Damaris Agweyu** - Site Owner damaris@kazilynk.com or agweyud@gmail.com +254 703 413 421

**Samuel Muiruri** – Main Developer <a href="mailto:support@kazilynk.com">support@kazilynk.com</a>

### +Color - pluscolor.co.ke

2017 – to date

Started by me (and still), **+Color** started as a gallery for images just showcasing example images transformed from black & white to coloured using machine learning, this also applied to images with color.

Example: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/colourizer">https://pluscolor.co.ke/colourizer</a>

The above led to the core concept behind the galleries:

- <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery">https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery</a>
- <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery?photo">https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery?photo</a> id=130
- https://pluscolor.co.ke/african-history

There's also the timeline which shows images shared by users (incuding the results from +Color Apps): <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/timeline">https://pluscolor.co.ke/timeline</a>

### +Color Apps

### Color Picker: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-picker">https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-picker</a>

Allows you to pick a color (by hex code) from an image by clicking the spot on the image. This is copied to your clipboard.

*Color Editor:* https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor

Allows you to edit an image using "color rules". *Example*: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor-example">https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor-example</a>

**Not yet launched** due to an issue configuring sockets... anyway here's a pre-socket launch recording: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&video">https://www.youtube.com/edit?o=U&video</a> id=JlNcbdE6Df4

*Color Delete:* https://pluscolor.co.ke/delete-color

Allows you to delete section(s) of an image: (works but without sockets)

Example: <a href="https://youtu.be/-EiCraPtVIY">https://youtu.be/-EiCraPtVIY</a>